If I'm going to beg or eat, I'm going to have to tell people.
But I can't start with Sylphie. If she breaks down in tears, I'll probably lose my nerve.
To steal myself, I'll tell Alina Lise first.
Correct me if I'm wrong, but I thought I told you to stay put.
Yeah, but I can't.
Okay, fine, if you insist. Shall we go together?
We shall. Thanks, Selina Lise.
I've never been to beg or eat before, but if we take the most straightforward, albeit the most dangerous route, it should take about eight months each way.
That's significantly faster than I'd estimated.
Yay for the wisdom of age!
Do not provoke me, Rudeus. The biggest issue I can see will be managing my curse on the road.
I'd love to help, but we're not going to be sleeping together.
No, of course not.
Couldn't we borrow the magical implement Cliff was making for you? It'll help relieve your symptoms.
Well, if I try to take it from him, he's bound to ask why, and then I'll cave and tell him everything.
You're not going to tell him you're leaving?
Hmm. Just go talk to the guy.
Not about breaking up. About your future.
Oh, very well.
A 16-month round trip. And if there's trouble in Rippon, it could be more like two years. I'd better start making the rounds.
Come in.
What's up? I wasn't expecting to see you today.
I know. I have some rather unfortunate news to share with you.
Well, go ahead and tell me.
I'm leaving school for the labyrinth city of Rippon on Begarit. I figure it'll be two years.
That's huge. You're leaving for two years? Really?
I know. I promised to help you, and I feel terrible. But listen, I have to make this journey.
Two years?
Um, I guess I'll be going.
Wait a sec.
Look at this.
What is it?
A map of ancient ruins, where you'll be able to find teleportation circles.
Huh?
That page shows you where to find a teleporter here in Sharia that will take you straight to Begarit.
Just like that.
I thought... You said you didn't remember where they were!
Yeah, well, that was kind of a lie.
I've heard about this Rappan place, though, and I know where it is.
Look, see this bazaar near the teleporter?
If you travel due north from there, you can reach Rappan in about a month.
Just one month? Really?
I could make it home before the baby is born.
Keep this to yourself, though, okay?
Teleportation magic is still forbidden.
If word gets out, all those ruins will be destroyed.
Nanohoshi, thank you.
I owe you one.
No, you don't. We're even now.
But we do need to keep working, so you'd better hurry up.
I will.
I've made up my mind. I'd like to help my parents.
Then you should. I'll take care of things here.
I know I promised you I wouldn't disappear. I'm sorry, Sylphie.
Don't be sorry. I don't consider this disappearing.
But, um, how long will you be gone? Two-ish years?
Actually, I talked to Nanohoshi about it, and she showed me where to find some teleportation circles.
So, I should be home before the baby is born.
Teleporting? You really think that's safe?
Don't worry. I'll come back in one piece.
Okay.
Aisha?
Oh, yes, sir?
Take care of her.
Okay, um, I can try.
If you run into any trouble, ask for help from people you trust. You don't have to do everything yourself.
Okay.
And Norn?
Yeah? What is it?
If these two get overwhelmed, make sure you're there for them, okay? Can you do that?
Yes.
Oh, and hey, let's pick a name for the baby before I have to go.
Um, you want to name the baby?
Rudy, big brother, why would you say something like that?
Rudy, yes?
They say if you name your baby before a long journey, then you'll never make it back.
Oh, are those famous last words in this world? Great.
How about this?
You can pick a proper name once you're back home, all safe and sound. But if the baby is born before then, we can call them Rudyus Jr.
That sounds good. What do you think, Sylphie? Does that work?
Yep.
I love you.
Once the details were ironed out, I made the rounds with everyone else.
I still haven't seen Badi Gadi since that one time at the house. But I'm sure he's fine.
I asked Vice Principal Genius for a leave of absence, and got permission to indefinitely borrow books on teleportation and the continent of Begarit.
They might come in handy.
The plan is this. We'll need to travel about a week from here to the forest where the ruins are located.
From there, we'll teleport to Begarit, find the bazaar, and take another month or so to reach Rippon.
Then we'll find my folks, bail them out, and hustle back home the same way we came. Perfectly cut and dried.
Last chance. You missing anything?
Nope. Got everything that I'll need.
Wait.
Hmm?
It's still far from perfect, but I was able to shrink it a little bit. And it's flexible.
So at least you can wear your clothes over it now.
Take care of Lise.
I will.
Oh, Cliff.
Lise.
When you get back, let's get married.
I know I haven't broken your curse yet, but I want to build a home with you.
I know I've waited a long time to say that.
You probably started to think I was all talk.
Really?
But I tried to leave without telling you. I'm a horrible woman.
You don't mind a Mili-style ceremony, do you?
I know you're not a follower, but...
Not at all.
My darling.
I love you more than anyone alive.
Rudy.
Sylphie.
I'll be home soon.
Norn, Aisha, you'll be good.
Don't worry. We can take care of everything here. We promise.
Best of luck, brother dearest.
Sylphie?
Chin up now. I won't let anything happen to Rudeus.
And we'll be home before that baby arrives.
I know. Take care of yourself too, Grandma.
Yes, never fear. I am a professional.
Well, we'd better go.
We'll miss you.
I don't know.
I think I found it. This is the stone, right?
It matches Nanohoshi's records. I'd say this is it.
Purge the barrier.
Lo, the dragon lived only for conviction.
Many tried, but none escaped the magnificent reach of his arms.
The second dragon to die, the general with the most ephemeral eyes,
the scales of green and silver.
In the name of Dragon Emperor Sherrod, I now declare this seal no more.
I've never seen magic like this before.
It looks like normal ancient ruins to me.
I'd say this isn't unusual for a labyrinth.
Don't be fooled. Keep an eye out for traps just in case.
Yes, ma'am.
That's suspicious.
Great.
I suppose that's the teleportation circle?
If I had to guess, yeah.
Let me check real quick.
That's quite a large book.
Exploring the teleporter labyrinth.
It's filled with info about teleportation circles.
Some details are different,
but this one definitely has all the signs of a two-way circle.
I found it while Sylphie and I were studying the mass teleportation in Fitoa.
I never expected to use it like this, though.
One more thing.
We need to be in physical contact when we teleport.
Is something wrong?
No.
It's just,
teleportation hasn't been too kind to me.
Not sure this will help,
but I know what you mean.
You do indeed.
Well then,
shall we?
Let's.
I guess it worked.
Looks like it did.
Let's check and see if we can make it back to the other side.
I'll go.
You stay here.
If this circle malfunctions and you disappear,
I'd prefer not to have to explain it to Paul.
Well, all right.
Mighty kind of you.
She's still not back?
It worked.
I made it back safe and sound.
You were gone for a long time, though.
Was I really?
I thought I came back after a few seconds.
Maybe there's a time lag.
No big deal.
Well, you made it back and that's what matters most.
This is it.
Welcome to the scorching desert sands of Bekarite.
This place is buried,
but that's not why it's hard to find.
There must be magic hiding it from outside,
though we can see out of it just fine.
What now?
Should we try and make some headway?
No, it's getting too dark.
We should rest here for the night.
When the sun goes down,
I'm afraid travel will be more difficult.
That means the air station would be the same as it cold.
Oh, oh.
Oh, oh, oh.
Oh, Cliff.
That was close.
I thought I was doing just fine, but I guess I'm more backed up than I realized.
My head's all fuzzy.
Luteus!
Keep it in your pants!
That's a succubus!
Disgusting.
What a foul stench.
Did she hurt you?
Hey, Eulina Lise, come on!
You know?
You've got a really nice body.
It'd be a shame to waste it.
Detoxify yourself, boy.
Hey, uh...
Eulina Lise?
I'm...
Sorry.
You didn't deserve all that.
You've got a really nice body.
Yeah.
A pretty nice comun mieć.
We'll be right back.
I'll be back. I'm going out for a bit.
Where are you going?
A little manhunting. Please don't bother waiting up for me.
Sure, all right.
Cliff's magical implement takes the edge off her curse for the most part, but I guess it still needs work.
For both our sakes, we better save Zenith soon and get the hell out of here.
Oh, hey, Rudeus. Do you see that up ahead?
Let's check it out.
Should we go around?
Hell no. Climb on. We're going up and over.
Thank you, dear. It's nice to have someone around with so much mana.
You can count on me. If there's an easier way, you know I'll find it.
Get down!
Two Griffins and two of us.
You deal with that one.
I'm on it.
Come on.
You're not going anywhere!
Here you go. Hot and fresh.
Thank you, Rudeus. I do love your seasoning.
I am to please.
You're a lady, right? Is it so hard to act like one?
My word. You're starting to sound just like your mother.
My mom used to scold you, too?
You're a lady, Alina Lys. Would it kill you to try and act like one?
Come to think of it, if I'm not mistaken, Zenith was about your age when I first met her.
Really? She was 16?
Yes. She was just a clueless little girl.
Paul picked her up off the street and dragged her into our party, the scoundrel.
By the way, I got the impression that Dad wants to apologize to you about something.
You mind if I ask what happened?
You're better off not knowing.
I don't think you want to hear too much about your father's messy love affairs, do you?
I don't. Thanks for the warning.
Knowing Paul, I can imagine the drama that followed his trail of exploits.
But still, I'm sure he'll apologize when we get to Rappan.
I won't forgive him, no matter what he says.
Looks like we finally made it.
Whoa.
Work.
La-ya-la-ya-la